南太平洋某处 1944年
金刚
骷髅岛
If we can put this tremendous machine of ours...
1945年12月
让我们致胜的强大军力
which has made this victory possible to work for peace...
如可运用于追求和平
We can look forward to the greatest age in the history of mankind
就能开创人类最伟大的时代
Speed of progress in the satellite project
卫星计划的进展速度
Cannot be taken as an index of our progress in ballistic missiles word.
不能作为弹道飞弹成果的进展指标
指令27:布拉沃城堡核子试爆
I feel we're on the brink of an area of expansion
我认为是时候大力扩展
of knowledge about ourselves and our surroundings
关于人类本身及其周遭
that is beyond description of comprehension at this time
在目前仍无法以言语形容或理解的知识
For the first time, we are putting cameras into space...
人类首次把摄影机放到太空
and looking down on the Earth...
俯视地球
allowing us to discover places and things we've never seen before.
让我们发现前所未见的地和物
The most intelligent inhabitants
最聪明的居民
of that future world won't be men or monkeys..
在未来世界里不会是人类或猴子
Thay'll will be machines.
而是机器
We set sail on this new sea...
我们于这片新的大海上启航
because there is new knowledge to be gained.
因为新的知识在等着被发掘
Whether this new ocean.
无论这片新的海洋
will be a sea of peace or a new terrifying theater of war.
会是和平之海或是可怕的新战场
To tame the savageness of man.
驯服人的野性
and make gentle the life of this world.
令世人活得温文儒雅
Let us dedicate ourselves to that.
让我们致力于此
1973年
The city wide protests
随着全市抗议
have brought congressional committee hearings to a standstill
国会听证陷入停顿
Promising more gridlock in the days and weeks ahead,
预见未来几周交通瘫痪会更严重...
the beltway is experiencing significant delays
环市公路大阻延
Mark my words
记住我的话
There will never be a more screwed up time in Washington.
华府不会有更糟糕的时刻了
But we can't let it stop us.
但我们不能因此却步
Come on already, let's go!
阻够了,走开
Get out of the way!
别挡路
Maybe now is not the best time to ask
现在不是开口的最好时机
Monarch is on the cusp of being shut down
君主即将关门大吉
Brooks. We are broke!
布鲁克,我们破产了
When this war ends,
战争一旦结束
we'll never get approval for our expedition.
我们的考察就无法获准
I am not confident in our presentation.
我对我们的简报没信心
I mean, all of our material are loose leaf.
我们的数据不够实在
In one day, one day,
再一天,只要一天
I could have all of this organized and bound
我能全部整理好
That we, today, have concluded an agreement...
今天,我们达成协议
to end the war and bring peace with honor in Vietnam.
结束战争为越南带来光荣的和平
All American forces will be withdrawn.
全体美军都会撤退
We don't have a day.
我们连一天都没有了
Hello there.
妳好
Bill Randa here to see Senator Willis.
比尔朗达来见韦尔斯参议员
Of course, Mr. Randa.
果然是你,朗达先生
I left you a message this morning
我今早留了讯息给你
about rescheduling today's appointment
今天约会要改期
But he should have some thing available in the coming weeks.
但他随后几周应该有空
Oh, god.
撞鬼!
Al, you're looking well.
艾尔,你气色真好
So you didn't get the message, Randa? To reschedule?
朗达,你没收到我的讯息?见面改期!
For the fifth time? I must have missed it
第5次?我一定没注意到
It'll be quick.
我们会速战速决
Okay, don't get comfortable. You got five minutes. I'm late for a meeting.
别坐得太舒服,你们只有5分钟,我开会要迟到了
So, what imaginary monster are you hunting this time?
这次你要捕猎什么想象中的怪兽?
This is a satellite photo of an uncharted island
这是一座未知岛屿的卫星照片
in the South Pacific.
在南太平洋上
It has defied discovery until now.
至今仍是隐密的处女地
Many civilizations spoke of it in legends.
许多文明的传说中都提到
Skull Island
骷髅岛
The land where God did not finish creation.
上帝未造完的国度
It is notorious for the number
有着为数不少的
of ships and planes that have gone missing there.
船只和飞机,在那里失踪
Like the Bermuda Triangle?
像是百慕达三角洲?
Or like aluminum foil hat that I like to wear in the weekends?
或像是我周末喜欢戴的防电波金属帽?
It's more like the triangle in the hat...
较为像三角洲,不像帽
but we like to think it's much more than that.
但应该没那么单纯
The 1954 Castle Bravo nuclear tests
1954年的布拉沃城堡核子试爆
Weren't a test.
其实不是试验
They were trying to kill something.
他们想杀掉某个东西
美国军舰神秘损毁
I believe there is an ecosystem out there
我相信那儿有一种生态系统
the likes of which we can't imagine
是超乎我们想象的
And the place to find it. Is this island.
会在这座岛上找到
A place where myth and science meet.
那里是超自然和科学的交界
Randa, it's a fairy tale.
朗达,好一个童话
Harry Truman didn't think so
杜鲁门总统不是这样想
when he funded Monarch in 1946.
当他于1946拨款给君主计划时
You know, in terms of sheer waste,
你知的 就单指浪费而言
Monarch ranks right up there in the search for alien life.
君主因搜寻外星生物名列前茅
Yeah, but those guys are nuts.
对,但那些人是疯子
We should have shut you down years ago.
几年前就该把你们关闭
This is an opportunity for our country.
这是我们国家的大好机会
Listen, Senator,
听着,参议员
Landsat is sending a mission to the Island
大地卫星打算派人去那座岛
We could piggybank on that operation.
我们能搭上那行动的顺风车
With your permission, of course.
当然一定要你的同意
What're you hoping you'll find?
你们认为会发现什么?
Resources, medicine, the cure for cancer,
资源、药材、癌症的解药
geological discoveries. I mean
或是地质发现
The possible alternative fuels, Senator, look, just...
可能的替代燃料,参议员
Listen, to be honest,
听着,老实说
we do not know for sure what's there.
我们不确定那里有什么
Okay. But I will tell you what we do know.
但我会告诉你我们知道什么
Tomorrow night,
明晚
the Russian Novosat passes over this sector.
俄国的诺佛卫星会经过这区
And in three days,
在三天内
they're gonna have the same images as we have
他们也会获得岛屿影像
So whatever's there,
所以不管那里有什么
You want us to find it first.
你会想是我们先找到
Right?
对吧?
I don't believe I'm saying this,
我不敢相信我会这样说
but that almost makes sense.
但那算是言之有理
Thank you.
谢谢
So I will get the piggybank for you. I will
我会安排你们搭顺风车
But listen to me, listen to me.
但听我说,听我说,就这样
This is it, It's gotta end. This is it
到此为止,就这样
You promise me? The last favor?
你向我保证无下次?
Okay?
好吗?
Senator
参议员
One last thing.
最后一件事
I'm going to need a military escort.
我会需要军事护卫
越南:岘港空军基地
第三突击直升机连,欢迎
Attention, all soldiers and base personnel.
注意,所有士兵和基地人员
Final troop withdrawal will commence at 0600.
最后的军队撤退将于6点开始
Pack your bags, ladies.
执好行李,姊妹们
We're going home.
我们要回家了
- Hey, Mills.   - Yeah?
- 嘻 米尔斯  - 什么事?
How many letters did you end up writing her?
你给她写了几封信?
Uh...ten, fifteen.
十到十五封吧
How many letters she write you?
她写给你几封?
I don't know, three, four.
不记得,三或四封
Man, you got a shitty mom.
老兄,你老妈子好差劲
Thankyou, Cole, for clearing that up. Thankyou.
谢谢柯尔,讲得这么白,唔该晒!
I'll be sure to tell her when I see her in the next 48 hours.
两天后见到她,一定会转告
Yeah, you might have a shitty mom.
是的,你老妈子的确差劲
Right?
对吧?
帕卡德 美国陆军
The United States is making it clear to the communists
美国要共产党明白
that American troop withdrawal is directly on the release of U.S. prisoners of war.
美国战俘一获释美军就会撤退
Washington notified the viet cong
华府今天已通知
and north vietnamese today that the withdrawal...
越共和北越关于撤退...
Sir?
长官
Chapman.
查普曼
第一军机旅
Do you need anything, sir?
长官,需要效劳吗?
帕卡德中校
All good.
没什么需要
Roger that.
了解
So what are you gonna do when you get back to the world, Chapman?
你回国后打算做什么?查普曼
Oh, I'm already set up with the Eastern Airlines.
我已经在东方航空谋得职位
Grace and Billy all moved in Atlanta, just
桂丝和比利都搬到亚特兰大
waiting on me.
正在等我回去
What about you sir?
长官,你呢?
All this for what?
这一切是为了什么?
Sir?
长官?
Get out of here, Chapman. Go have some fun.
查普曼,走吧,去找点娱乐
Is everything okay?
没什么事吧?
Tip-top
一切都很好
Colonel Packard!
帕卡德中校
There's a phone call for you.
那边有电话找你
This is Packard.
我是帕卡德
Packard, It's General Ward.
帕卡德,我是华德将军
You and your boys up of one last op?
你和你的士兵愿意执行最后一次任务?
I would not be opposed to that, sir.
我不反对,长官
Yours order to head home are already processed.
已经通过你们的返家指令
Sure you don't wanna to take some time?
你真的不想休息一下?
I'm here to execute whatever orders I'm given, sir.
我会奉命执行任何下达的指令,长官
Ah, don't get too excited.
别兴奋过头了
Bunch the scientists called Landsat, discovered a new island on their Satellite.
一群大地卫星的科学家发现一座新岛屿
They need helicopter transport for a survey job.
他们需要直升机运输协助调查工作
Roger that
了解
- And sir?   - Yes?
- 还有长官...  - 什么事?
Thank you
谢谢你
生活杂志特刊,1973年
年度大事照片集
Randa, I don't get it.
朗达,我不懂
You already got us a military escort.
你已经争取到军事护卫
Why do we need a tracker? And why SAS?
为什么还要追踪人员?而且是特种兵?
西贡:泉南
Former SAS. No allegiance to anyone.
前特种兵,不效忠任何人
And he rescued 12 downed pilots in Danang, at '72.
1972年他在岘港救了12名坠机飞行员
But your source says that he spends most of his
但你的情报说他清醒的大多时间
waking hours in some back alley watering hole.
都在后巷酒吧混
Is your Yale degrees supposed to
布鲁克,你的耶鲁学历
lead us through the Jungle, Brooks?
能带领我们穿越丛林吗?
Beside, my father told me never judge a man by where he drinks,
何况我爸说别从喝酒的地方判断人
Only how he holds it.
而是从酒品判断
You on board with me here?
你认同我吗?
You go.
进去吧
Well. Okay.
好 好吧
So, uh, how much do we tell him?
我们要向他透露多少?
Just enough to get him to say yes.
只要让他答应就够了
这样就想走
把钱留下,不然要你好看
你小子给我听好了
这里是我的地盘,你识相点
Now there is a man worth talking to.
总算值得跟他倾一倾
An uncharted island?
一座未知的岛屿?
Let me list all they ways you're gonna die.
让我列出你的各种死法
Rain, heat, mud,
暴雨、高温、烂泥
disease carrying flies and mosquitoes.
苍蝇和蚊子传染的疾病
Sure you can load up on the Atabrine for the malaria.
当然,你能带着疟疾药
but what about the other bacteria?
但其它细菌呢?
And we haven't even started on the things
我们甚至还未提到
that want to eat you alive.
想生吞你的东西
We'll double that.
钱加倍
You have no idea how dangerous this is.
你两个根本唔识死
I want five times that.
我要五倍
Plus a bonus if we make it back.
如果我们能回来,另加奬金
If?
"如果"?
Pay him.
付他
I think Mr. Conrad should be fairly compensated.
康拉德先生他...应该获得合理报酬
Here is to profit during peacetime.
敬你和平时期能捞一笔
One question.
有个问题
You came here looking for a tracker.
你们来找追踪手
Who or what am I tracking?
我要追踪谁或什么?
This is all the information that we have.
我们的信息仅只于此
Okay? There is no map.
没有地图
Only satellite images.
只有卫星影像
So we need someone like you
所以我们需要你这种高手
with your skill and unique expertise in unchartered jungle terrain
凭着你在未知丛林地带的技能和独特专业
to lead us on our ground expedition.
领导我们展开地面探索
We're just scholars and scientists.
我们只是学者和科学家
We need someone with experience.
我们需要有实地经验的人
In case things go sideways.
以免出状况
Men go to war in search of something, Mr. Conrad.
自愿参战的人往往为了追寻某样东西
If you found it,
如果追寻到
you would be home by now.
你老早就回家了
Weaver.
玮桦
Yeah, it's Jerry.
我是谢利
Hey, Jerry.
嗨,谢利
So, tell me, did I get it?
告诉我 获聘了吗?
That Landsat thing?
大地卫星之旅?
You got it
妳获聘了
I did?
真的?
Hello?
喂?
there is the Athena docked in Bangkok.
阿西娜号,停靠在曼谷
Pier 14, 6'o clock tomorrow night.
14号码头,明晚6点
1800 tomorrow.
明晚6点
Thank you. I really owe you one.
谢谢,我欠你个人情
I don't get it.
我不懂
Why do you want a gig documenting a mapping mission?
妳为何想要记录勘测任务?
When you're up on the cover of Time?
妳劲到可登时代杂志封面
Jerry, when three sources tell you the same thing word for word,
谢利,当三个来源一字不差地告诉你同一件事
You know they are lying.
你会知道他们在说谎
There is something going on here,
事有蹊跷
something that nobody is talking about.
某个不能说的秘密
泰国:曼谷
14号码头
阿西娜号
I can't believe we're doing this. Are you guys kidding me?
我们居然要执行任务,离谱!
A day away? One day away!
多留一天,就差一天!
And, no, now we gotta go to another Island
何况还是去另一座岛
with another jungle.
有另一座丛林
Vietnam is not a island, Dumbass.
越南不是岛,笨蛋
Well, Key West is,
佛州西屿就是
and that's exactly where I need to be right now,
那才是我们该去的地方
with a drink in my hand.
手上拿红酒叹着
Key West ain't an island, either. It's a key.
西屿也不算是岛,小如礁石
You ain't funny, Cole.
唔好笑,柯尔
Mason Weaver, photographer.
我是梅森?玮桦,摄影师
Mason Weaver is a woman?
梅森?玮桦是女的?
last time I checked
我检查过是的
Can I help you?
需要帮忙吗?
Two years in the country. Where have you been?
在境内两年,妳加入哪机构?
Embedded with MAC V-SOG.
安插在美国情报单位
Ah, you were in the shit. I respect that.
妳还真有胆识,向妳致敬
But It's people like you,
但就是妳这种人
lost us support back home.
害我们失去国民支持
You aren't actually gonna blame the people without guns
你不会责怪没拿枪的人
for losing the war, are you?
打败仗吧?
Camera's way more dangerous than a gun.
相机比枪炮还危险
And we didn't lose the war
而且我们没有打败仗...
We abandoned it.
我们是打厌了
Right.
对
Hello and welcome.
各位好,欢迎
I am Lansat field supervisor, Victor Nieves
我是大地卫星的实地监督维特尼夫
this is my collegue,
这是我的同事
Steve Woodward
史提夫?胡活
Our data wrangler
资料分析员
Our expedition takes us to a place
我们要探索的地方
Every nautical trade route
所有航海贸易路径
known to man has avoided for centuries.
是几世纪以来的禁地
As our satellite shows,
卫星显示这座岛
the island is surrounded by a perpetual storm system,
长期受到风暴系统包围
allowing it to remain hidden from the outside world.
至使它始终隐藏于世
But with Colonel Packard's helicopter transport,
帕卡德中校的直升机
we will be the first to break through to the other side.
令我们得以成为深入这秘地的首例
We're also pleased to be joined, for the fisrt time
我们第一次有
by the resource exploration team
资源探勘团队随行
led by Mr. Randa,
领军的朗达先生
and the company by biologist, Ms. San
和队员生物学家珊小姐
and geologist, Mr. Brooks.
以及地质学家布鲁克先生
Our focus will be on the Island's surface
我们会专注于岛的地面
Theirs, what lies beneath.
他们则专注地底
Mr Brooks.
布鲁克先生
Simple, really
其实很简单
We'll use explosives to shake the earth and create vibrations
我们会用炸药,制造陆地震动
helping us to map the subsurface of the island.
通过震波帮助我们勘测地底
We will fly in over the south shore,
我们会飞往南岸上方
and then strategically drop seismic chargers to better help us
策略性地投下炸药包
understand the density of the earth.
帮助我们了解陆地密度
You are dropping bombs?
你们要投弹?
Scientific instruments.
是科学仪器
Do you hear that, boys?
兄弟们,听到未?
We are scientists, now
我们变成科学家了
You guys are not scientists.
你们才不是科学家
We'll then land and make base camp
接着会登陆,建基地营
for ground excursions led by Mr. Conrad.
再由康拉德先生带领在地面游走
Major Jack Chapman.
积克?查普曼少校
All right. Once on the island
好,一旦登上那座岛
the storm interference will block all radio contact with the ship.
风暴的干扰会阻挡船上所有无线电
That means, we will be by ourselves
那表示我们只能靠自己
Three days later,
三天后
the refuel team will meet us here, on north end of the island.
燃料补给队会到岛北和我们会合
That might be our only safe departure for an unknown period of time.
那可能是唯一能够安全的离开时机
So, tip for everybody,
所以给各位的忠告
don't miss it, please.
千万别错过,拜托了
禁区,闲人勿进
美军 7.62mm子弹
大地卫星
What are you doing down here?
妳在这里做什么?
I could ask you the same thing.
我才应该问你
Why does a geological mapping mission needs explosives.
为什么地质勘测需要炸弹?
You weren't listening in class
妳没专心听课
Seismic charges for the geological survey.
是地质勘探用的炸药包
Uh-huh. You believe that?
是喔,你相信那一套?
I didn't say that.
我可没说
Have you met Colonel Packard yet?
你见过帕卡德中校了吗?
Yeah.
见过了
The guy is bound pretty tight
那家伙受创很深
Wee, the man's a decorated war hero. That's the package they come in
他是战功彪炳的英雄,难免那副模样
And you?
那妳呢?
Isn't shooting a mapping mission
拍摄勘测任务
a step down for a photojournalist?
不会让摄影记者却步吗?
The right photo can help shape opinions.
适当的照片有助于形成舆论
And win you a Pulitzer.
还为妳赢得普立兹奖
Okay, Captain Conrad.
好,康拉德上尉
What about you?
那你呢?
How did British Special forces get dragged into this?
英国特种兵怎会卷入这场行动?
Just "Conrad". I'm decommissioned.
叫康拉德就好,我退役了
They offered me money.
他们花钱请我
You don't strike me as a mercenary.
我看你不像佣兵
You don't strike me as a war photographer.
我看妳不像战地摄影师
Anti-war photographer.
反战摄影师
What are you writing there, Chap?
查普曼,你在写什么?
Letter to my boy.
写信给我儿子
"Dear Billy"
"亲爱的比利"
"I know I said I would be home by your birthday,"
"我说会在你生日前回家"
"but I lied straight to your face."
"但我当着你的面说谎"
"I'm a terrible dad."
"是个糟糕爸爸"
"I hope this letter makes up for it."
"希望这封信会补偿你"
That's too short.
太短了啦
阿西娜号
This storm looks a lot nastier in person.
这场风暴亲眼看起来更凶险
Maybe we should consider postponing the mission.
也许该考虑押后任务
How far away is this island?
离这座岛还有多远?
50 miles. maybe more.
50英里,也许更远
Take us closer.
带我们靠近点
You wanna launch, you do it from here.
想飞就从这里起飞
Can you punch through that, Colonel?
中校,你们能穿越风暴吗?
- Our opening is now.   - Through this hole right here?
- 我们的机会就是现在  - 穿过这个洞?
Yeah, it's a rare low-pressure pocket.
是难得的低压气穴
I appreciate your passion, Randa
我欣赏你的热诚,朗达
but as a field supervisor of the controlling agency,
但身为控制机构的实地监督
I say we abort. that's it, we are gonna abort.
我建议终止任务!就这样,终止任务
Wise call.
明智决定
I'm sure the Landsat inspector
大地卫星的视察员
will be inspired by your courage.
一定会被你的勇气激励
I hope he'll be inspired by my common sense.
不,他会受到我的常识激励
This is only a map survey.
这只是地图侦测
To one of the last unchartered areas on the face of the earth.
对于地表最后的未知区域之一
And you want to call it on account of rain?
你却因下雨而放弃?
Stay on the boat if you want to.
想待在船上随你
It could be years before we get another shot at this.
我们要等好几年才再有这种机会
I'm told your unit is capable of handling inclement weather, Colonel.
中校,听说你的部队能够应付这种狂暴天气
Why don't we leave it to Colonel Packard to break the tie?
就让帕卡德中校打破困局吧
There is no way I'm getting on that helicopter.
打死我都不会坐上那直升机
We did ask to arm those helicopters.
我们要求武装直升机
Shouldn't they know why?
他们不该知道原因吗?
Why? And raise an alarm?
原因?引起大惊小怪?
Purely a precaution, Brooks.
布鲁克,纯粹作预防
Right.
是喔
Two Mike till launch.
再过2分钟起飞
Troops and civilians, board assigned aircraft
军队和平民登上指定飞机
Two Mike till launch.
再过2分钟起飞
What's the old man getting us into, Cole?
柯尔,那条老家伙真好带挈
Nothing he wouldn't do himself. He is taking the lead.
他不怕亲力亲为,就由他带头
Doesn't he miss his bed? I miss my bed!
他不想念家里的床吗?我想念我的
Don't you miss your bed?
你也想念你的床吧?
Do you even have a bed, Cole?
柯尔,你没有床吗?
You got a bed, right?
你有床吧?
See you at the rendevzous, Chapman.
查普曼,在会合点见
Yes sir.
是,长官
One Mike thirty. Repeat, one Mike thirty to launch
一分三十秒,重复,一分三十秒后起飞
炸药包
汽油
Complete FOD walkdown, and clear the deck.
完成机外异物检查,清空甲板
One Mike to launch.
再过一分钟起飞
- Battery?   - Check.
- 电池?  - 已检查
- Generator start?   - Check, check
- 发电机启动?  - 正常 正常
- Engine start?   - Checked three times.
- 引擎启动?  - 检查三遍了
This is Fox Leader of the Fox Group.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
It is time, once again,
该是时候再一次
for the Griffin and ants show.
让狮鹫和蚂蚁登场
As usual, remember,
如常切记
hold on to your butts!
屁股要坐稳
Attention pilots. You are cleared for takeoff.
注意,飞行员,准许起飞
Launch, launch, launch.
起飞,起飞,起飞
Combat formation.
战斗状态队形
Keep visual.
保持可目视距离
Fox Five let me know when you close.
狐5号,靠近时通知我
Fox Five is in the slot.
狐5号就位
Roger that.
收到
Fox Team, form up on me. Keep it together!
狐小队,列队跟着我,一起行动
Let's do this!
大家冲了
Maintain course.
维持路线
Nothing we haven't done before.
我们什么场面没见过
Dear Billy.
"亲爱的比利"
You ever look inside a hurricane and decide?
"你曾经凝视飓风并决定"
Maybe I should flash straight through it.
"也许我该直接飞入穿过?"
because that's what's about to happen.
"因为那即将发生了"
Dear Billy, you might wanna hang on.
亲爱的比利,你最好抓紧了
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Switch to inertial navigation.
转为惯性导航
And remember the story of Icarus
记住伊卡洛斯神话
whose father gave him wings made of wax
他父亲给他蜡造的翅膀
and warned him not to fly too close to the sun.
并警告他别飞得太靠近太阳
But the exhilaration was too great.
但他太兴奋了
So he flew higher and higher
于是他愈飞愈高
until the sun melted his wings
直到太阳熔化了他的翅膀
and he fell into the sea.
他就跌入海中
But the United States Army is not an irresponsible father.
但美国陆军不是失职的父亲
So they gave us wings of white-hot, cold-rolled
他们给我们的翅膀是热炼冷压的
Pennsylvania steel.
宾夕法尼亚州精钢
Guaranteed not to melt.
保证不会熔化
Oh hey, that's pretty, huh?
景色很美吧?
Let's take them down, low and level.
贴近地面,保持低飞
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Split up, survey your zones.
分头调查各自的区域
Fox Seven, put landsat on deck.
狐7号,让大地卫星人员登陆
Copy, Fox Leader. Fox three headed to "Zone Six"
收到,狐队长,狐3号前往第6区
Put us down over there.
在那里把我们放下来
Everyone else, stay with the team leader.
其它人跟着队长
Move that gear to our three o'clock. Let's go, Let's move it!
把起落架移向3点钟方向,动作快
系统待命
Ready for seismic chargers.
准备投炸药包
Roger that.
收到
Fox Group, let it fly.
狐小队,可以投了
Copy all. Fox Three. Heading 0-9-0.
收到,狐3号,往正东方
Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
我没看错吧
The seismic response is incredible.
地震反应太激烈了
Hey, Randy, you're not gonna believe this.
朗达,你一定不会相信
The bedrock,
岩床
It's practically hollow.
实际上是空的
Incoming!
注意前方!
Look out!
小心
On guard, Fox Five!
保持警戒,狐5号
Fox Eight is down! Fox Four is down!
狐8号坠落,狐4号坠落
Respond, Fox Three!
狐3号,请回复!
Oh My God!
我的天啊
Fox Seven moving into position, three o'clock.
狐7号移入3点钟位置
Does anyone know what that is?
到底是什么东西?
I don't know, man.....God dammit...
我不知道,该死...
Three klicks west of red L.Z.
红色降落区以西3公里
Jesus! I've never saw anything like it!
天!我从没看过这种怪兽
Set a perimeter of 300 meters. Do not engage.
设定周边300公尺,不要开火
Roger, climb 1,800
收到,爬升1800公尺
Is that a monkey?
是猴子吗?
What the hell is that?
什么鬼东西?
Somebody talk to me, man.
谁回答我啊
Turn right, heading 2-5-0. Contact approach...
右转,往西南西,目标接近...
Fox Leader to Fox Group.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Form a perimeter.
包围周边
Ready gunners positions.
炮手预备位置
Holy shit! Look at that thing!
得人惊!看看那东西!
I'm freaking out here!
我给吓疯了!
Fox Leader to Fox Group. Fire at will!
狐队长呼叫狐小队,随意开火
- What the hell is that?   - I don't know!
- 那到底是什么?  - 不知道
Pull out now. Pull out.
马上撤离,撤离
I don't take orders from you!
我可不是听你的命令
Get us the hell out of here!
快带我们离开这里
Fox Nine is down!
狐9号坠落
Fox Six, we got nominal control.
狐6号,我们快失控了
We are going down.
我们要坠落了
Fox Five, this is Fox Leader. Fox Nine is down.
狐5号,这是狐队长,狐9号坠落
1 klick north of the river bend.
河弯以北一公里
Insert recovery team.
派出营救队
Over
完毕
Fox Five is hovering.
狐5号停留在空中
We got men going out the door.
我有机员降到地面了!
I need help here. I need...
我需要帮助,我需要...
Oh, shit!
不好了
Kill this son of a bitch.
宰了这畜牲
Coming in hot! I got eyes on it!
进攻,我看到了
Pull up!
升高!
Brace for impact!
准备面临冲击
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
求救!求救!求救!
Run this side, you idiot!
往旁边跑,你个笨蛋
Hang on
抓紧了
Watch out!
小心
Oh, God!
天啊
Prepare to crash!
准备坠机
Brace!
做好准备
Fox Leader is down!
狐队长坠落
Fox Five inbound to pickup!
狐5号回去接应
We have him in sight.
我们看到他了
Hold tight, Colonel Packard, We're on our way!
撑住,帕卡德中校,我们正赶过去
Hang on, Briggs. I'm coming.
撑着,布里吉,我来救你
We're going down.
我们要坠落了
I repeat, we are going down!
重复,我们要坠落了
Listen, I want you to tell me something right now.
听着,立刻回答我
- Do you love your mama?   - I love her!
- 你爱你老妈吗?  - 我爱她
- How much do you love your mama?   - I love my mama so much!
- 你多爱你老妈?  - 我超爱我老妈
发射
Calling all units! Is anybody airborne?
呼叫所有单位,有人在空中吗?
I repeat, is anybody airborne?
重复,有人在空中吗?
They're all down. Everyone of them.
所有人都坠落了,每一架机
We are on the south side of the island.
我们在岛的南边
There is a river a couple of klicks from here.
几公里外有一条河
If we sticks to its banks,
沿着河堤走
we'll make it to the EXFIL site on the north shore.
就会到达北岸的撤出点
And then what? All our choppers are down.
然后呢?所有直升机都坠落了
We'll find a way to signal the ship.
我们会想办法向船发信号
They'll send a search party.
他们会派出搜索队
We just have to make it by the exit window.
我们只要在撤离时间内到达
I should be sitting at a desk.
我们该坐办公桌的
So, wait, are we just not gonna talk about this?
等等,大家不先讲明白吗?
My best guess is we're scattered over 4 to 5 miles radius.
我估计大家散落在4到5英里半径范围
We must head north and join anyone we find.
该往北走,路上联合任何生还者
Are you all right?
妳没事吧?
I don't know how to answer that question right now.
我现在回答不到这个问题
I don't know what that was either.
我也不知道那是什么?
All that money that they paid you? I hope you're worth it.
他们付你多少钱?希望你值那个价
You really not gonna talk about it?
大家真的都不讲明白?
You know, this is not normal, right?
这不正常,对吧
Stuff like that doesn't just happen!
这种事不会平白发生!
This is Fox Leader to Fox group.
狐队长呼叫狐小队
Anybody with ears, come back. Respond. Over.
听到的人快回复!请回应,完毕
Fox, Chapman.
狐队长,查普曼
Fox Six, Chapman.
狐6号,查普曼
Say again your last.
再说一次你的坐标
4 klicks west, highest peak...
西方4公里,最高峰...
November Alpha 3-0-0. Over.
坐标3-0-0,完毕
Roger that, Chapman. West highest mountain peak.
了解,查普曼,西方最高山峰
Over.
完毕
Fox Six confirmed, we're the Sea Stallion.
狐6号确认,我们在海种马直升机旁
Chapman, hold your position.
查普曼,留在原地
We will come to you. There's enough munitions on that sea stallion to kill this thing.
我们会过去找你,海种马上的军火足以杀死那怪物
Survey your perimeter.
调查你的周边
Locate possible ambush sites. Over.
找出可能的埋伏地点,完毕
Chapman.
查普曼
Reles.
罗里斯
Taking a non R and R day, or you good to go?
你要休息还是现在就走?
I'm good to go, sir.
我现在走,长官
Get him up.
跟上来
Chapman, all stations.
查普曼呼叫所有岗位
Recon environment.
侦察环境
Cole, what's wrong with you?
柯尔,你有什么毛病?
How you even got an appetite right now?
你怎么现在还有胃口?
Eating is for the living.
进食是为了存活
We just got taken down by a monkey the size of a building!
我们刚被一只摩天大楼高的猴子击落了!
Yeah!
是啊
That was an unconventional encounter.
那是很不寻常的遭遇
Is that really all your brain telling itself right now?
你是不是吓呆了吗?
There's no tactical precedence.
这没有作战先例
We did the best we could in the situation.
这种情况下,我们尽了力
Griffin. Cole.!
狮鹫小队,柯尔!
Thank God you guys are okay!
谢天谢地你们没事
- Good to see you, sir.   - We're all right.
- 很高兴见到你,长官  - 我们没事
How many left?
剩下多少人?
Seven survivors.
七人生还
Seven confirmed KIA.
七人确认阵亡
Galleta, Saraf, and Hodges.
贾勒塔、萨拉夫、哈吉斯
Slivko, and the rest are unknown.
史利哥和其它人下落不明
Where is Randa?
朗达在哪里?
How you doing?
你还好吗?
I'm fine. Thank you.
我很好,谢谢
Good.
那好
Glad to hear it. I was worried about you.
很高兴听到,我还担心你了
You are going to tell me
你要从实招来
everything I don't know,
所有我不知道的事
or I'm gonna blow your head off.
否则我一枪打死你
Monsters exist.
怪兽确实存在
No shit.
废话
Nobody believed me.
没人相信我
Yesterday, I was a crackpot.
昨天,我被看作怪胎
But today.
但今天...
So, This was never about geology.
所以这从来就跟地质无关
You dropped those charges to flush something out.
你们投炸药包是要逼出怪物
Who are you?
你是什么来头?
You heard of the USS Lawton?
你听过美国军舰劳顿号吗?
Neither did the public
民众也没听过
Out of the thousand young men on that ship
那艘船上有一千名年轻人
I was the only survivor.
我是唯一的幸存者
They told my family she was sunk in battle,
他们告诉我家人,军舰被击沉
but I know what I saw.
但我知道我看到什么
It had no conscience.
No reasoning, just destroy
没头没脑,只是破坏
I spent the last 30 years...
我花了过去30年
trying to prove the truth
试图证明
of what I learned that day.
那天我得知的真相
This planet doesn't belong to us.
地球不属于我们
Ancient species owned this earth long before mankind.
古老物种早在人类之前就拥有地球
And if we keep our heads buried in the sand,
如果我们继续抱着鸵鸟心态
they will take it back
My agency is known as Monarch.
我的机构名为"君主"
We specialize in the hunt for massive unidentified terrestrial organisms
我们专精于捕猎巨大不明陆栖生物
You knew that thing was out here?
你早就知道那个怪物在这里?
I'm sorry for your men, Colonel. I truly am.
很遗憾你的属下罹难,我是真心的
Get us home with proof.
送我们回家,带着证据
So we can send the cavalry.
我们就能派来装甲部队
I'm the cavalry.
我就是装甲部队
It's called the Hollow Earth Theory.
这称为"地空说理论"
Randa hired me
朗达雇用我
because I wrote paper
因为我写了一篇论文
substantiating what most people think is a crackpot idea.
想证实多数人会认为异想天开的概念
That there are these massive underground spaces
主张地下藏有巨大空间
isolated from the surface world.
与地表世界隔离
Passageways. Randa believed this island may be one of those.
但有通道相连,朗达相信这座岛可能就是通道之一
An emergence point for whatever lives below.
地底不明生物的出没地点
Ancient species like what we just saw.
像是刚才看到的古老物种
I thought he was out of his mind.
我以为他疯了
This is Slivko, do you read?
我是史利哥,有听到吗?
Anybody out there?
还有人吗?
We are headed north to the EXFIL location
我们要往北去撤出点
Everyone here seems way too calm right now.
这里的每个人看起来太冷静了
Do you copy? Anybody?
收到吗?有人吗?
We're out of range, Slivko.
史利哥,我们超出收讯范围了
Oh, shit.
该死
Save it for when we get closer to the group.
留着接近团队时再用
Nobody move.
谁都不准动
Easy.
冷静
- Silvko.   - What?
- 史利哥  - 什么?
Put it down.
把枪放下来
These men did not die in vain.
这些人不是白白牺牲
I swear to God,
我对天发誓
their deaths will not go unanswered.
他们的死不会没有回报
Now, Let's get to Chapman and those munitions.
快去找查普曼和那些弹药
You ever heard of the story of the mouse, lion and the Thorn?
你听过老鼠、狮子和刺的故事?
Yeah.
听过
There you go then.
那你就懂了
In case we ever see that primate again.
以免我们又撞见那只猩猩
You do know that the story is about a mouse becoming friends with a lion
你知道故事中老鼠把狮子脚掌的刺拔出
after taking the Thorn out of his paw though, right?
之后成为好朋友吧?
No it's not.
才不是
The mouse kills the lion with the Thorn.
老鼠用刺杀死狮子
Who told you that, Cole?
谁告诉你的?
My mother.
我妈
That actually explains a lot.
怪不得你这么天真
Look out! Oh, shit!
小心,不妙
- Watch out!   - What is that?
- 小心  - 那是什么?
- Watch your six!   - Up above!
- 小心后方  - 在上面
Up in the trees! Guns up!
在树上,向上开枪
Cole!
柯尔
No, no! Mills!
不要,不要!米尔斯!
We got you!
我们帮你
I can't get a shot!
我瞄不准
Cut the legs! Cut it off at the legs!
砍断脚,砍断牠的脚
I got you!
有我在
Shake it off, guys! Let's move out
别想了,快上路
Stay tight
跟紧
What the hell is this?
这又是什么东西?
Go, Behind you!
注意后面
Everybody, stay calm. Stay calm.
大家保持,冷静,保持冷静
Conrad.
康拉德
Stay back!
后退
- Guys.   - Stop, stop.
- 大伙儿  - 别靠近,别靠近
- Stop, stop stop stop!   - Nobody shoot! Nobody shoot.
- 停、停、停、停  - 谁都不准开枪,不准开枪
Wow wow wow wow wow wow...
别 别 别 别 别..别这样
No, no, no. No need for that.
不,不,不,不必动枪
Come on now!
别激动
Everybody keep your wigs on now!
各位,镇定下来
What?
什么?
I didn't believe it when they said you were coming.
他们说你们来了,我还不信
I was up all night
我整晚没睡
just thinking about how me and Gunpei dreamed of this moment.
想着我和军平,梦想着这一刻
And now here it is.
如今实现了
Twenty-eight years, 11 months
28年又11个月
and eight failed attempts to get back to the world
八次尝试回归世界都失败
and instead, the world comes to me?
结果却是你们来找我?
Ain't that a crack?
不是很搞笑吗?
They never smile.
他们从不笑的
Did you crash here?
你在这里坠机?
Oh. Sorry miss.
失礼了,小姐
Lieutenant Hank Marlow of the 45th.
第45步兵团的汉克?马隆中尉
Put the old flight suit on for you
为了妳穿上旧飞行服
You are more beautiful
妳美多了...
than a hotdog and a beer
比起热狗配啤酒
at Wrigley Field on opening day.
在雷格利球场的开幕日
But you're real.
但妳是真实的
Right?
对吧?
I told you. Didn't I tell you?
我就说过,一早告诉你们
I Said,
我说
"It's fine".
"不要紧的"
There we go.
这样才对
There's something out there, man.
外面有怪物
Oh, there's a lot out there.
外面怪物可多了
Now, Come on. We gotta get home.
过来,我们快回家
You don't want to be out here at night.
晚上最好别在外面四围蘯
You probably noticed a lot of weird things on this Island
你们可能有注意到这座岛上有许多怪事
As long as we stay in here where the people live, we'll be all right.
只要待在这个部落里,大家就不会有事
That wall, is that supposed to keep out that thing?
那道墙是为了阻挡那只怪兽?
No, he's not the one they're trying to keep out.
不,他们想阻挡的不是牠
What?
什么?
These people live up in the top of the trees, while we are down in the roots.
这些人住在树上,不像我们住在地面
Some of them don't even seem to age.
有些人甚至看不出变老
There's no crime
没有犯罪
No personal property.
没有私人财产
They're past all that.
他们不在乎那一切
Thank you Thank you.
谢谢,谢谢
So, good news.
好消息
They say you can shack up here.
他们说你们能住这里
I didn't hear them say anything.
我没听到他们说话
Oh, they don't speak too much.
他们话不多
When you've been here as long as I have, you start to understand, You'll see.
要是你待在这里跟我一样久,就会明白
Wait a minute. Wait, wait, wait.
等一下,等等,等等,等等
We can't stay here. We have to get off the island.
我们不能留下,我们要离开这座岛
We have lives. I have a life.
我们有人生,我有人生
Nieves, now is not the time. All right?
尼夫,现在时机不对,明白吗?
What lands here tends to stay here.
踏上这里,就别想走了
漫游者号
As far as I can tell,
就我所知
this ship washed up about 10 years before I did.
这艘船比我早10年冲上岸
You've been here since '44?
你自1944年就在这里?
Yeah
对
Hey, what happened with the war? Did we win?
那场战争的结果呢?我们赢了?
Which one?
哪场战争?
That makes sense.
那说得通
This is all hallowed ground to them.
这是他们的圣地
So if you like your hands, don't touch anything.
不想断手的人,就别手多多
Look at that.
快看啊
The way they tell it, for thousands of years,
以他们的说法,几千年来
the people on this island lived in fear
这座岛上的人活在恐惧中
That's a hell of a long time to be scared.
真是害怕了很久
And then, one day, the damnedest thing happened.
然后有一天,最诡异的事发生了
Some of the things they were afraid of
他们害怕的东西
started protecting them against the things that were eating them.
开始保护他们免于被其它怪兽吃掉
But nothing lasts forever, I guess.
但凡事都不是永恒的吧,我猜
And this is where they honor the last of their saviors.
他们在这里奉祀最后的救主
Yeah.
是啊
That's Kong.
那是金刚
He is king around here.
He is God to these people.
这些人供牠为神
Kong's a pretty good king.
金刚是个好国王
Keeps to himself mostly
习惯独来独往
This is his home. We are just guests here.
这是牠的家,我们只是客人
But you don't go into someone's house and start dropping bombs
最好不要到别人家里投弹
unless you're picking a fight.
除非你五行欠打
Wasn't Kong the one who killed your friend?
不是金刚杀了你朋友?
No.
不是
One of them did.
这种怪兽杀的
Kong's God on the island,
金刚是这座岛上的神
but the devils live below us.
但在地底之下有恶魔
And what are they called?
叫什么名字?
The Iwis won't speak their name.
伊维族不会说出牠们的名字
But I call them skull-crawlers.
但我称牠们为爬骨兽
Why?
为什么?
'Cause it's sounds neat.
听起来有劲度
Okay.
好吧
Look, I just made that name up. I am trying to scare you.
我编出那个名字,想吓吓大家
I'm fine calling them that.
那名字无问题
- Are you cool with that?   - Yeah
- 你同意吗?  - 同意...
I like the name, so... That seems like a great name.
我喜欢那个名字,是个好名字
I've never said that name out loud before, it sounds stupid now that I say it. Just..
我从未公开过这名字,听自己讲都骨痹
You call them whatever you want.
你们想怎么叫都可以
They're big lizard things. Nasty.
是一种大蜥蜴,异常凶猛
They come from the vents deep down.
来自地底深处的裂缝
That's why Kong got so mad.
难怪金刚会发神经
Those bombs woke up a bunch of them.
那些炸弹会唤醒其中几只
I tell you what, you're luckey he's out there, too
说实话,好彩金刚也在外面
or you wouldn't have made it this far.
否则你们活不到现在
They're crafty bastards. Mean as hell.
Now, he can handle them as long as he gets to them when they're still small.
只要牠们还小,金刚就对付得了牠们
You don't wanna wake up the big one.
你不会想要唤醒那只大的
- How big is it?   - It's bigger
- 有多大?  - 比较大
It wiped out his whole family.
消灭了牠全家
Kong's the last of his kind, but he's still growing.
金刚是同类中仅存的,但牠仍在长大
And you better hope he does.
你们最好希望牠是
Because the Iwis say once Kong goes,
因为伊维族说,金刚一去
then the big one comes up.
大恶魔就会出现
Then it's "goodnight, Irene."
那就大祸临头了
Listen, there is a refueling team
听着,有一支燃料补给队
coming to the north end of the island in three days.
三天后会抵达岛北
You should come with us.
你应该跟我们走
To the north end of the island?
到岛的北边?
We're gonna get out of here.
我们要离开这里
- In three days?   - Yes.
- 在三天内?  - 对
You can't get to the north end in three days.
不可能在三天内到达北边
It's impossible. That's it. No way.
不可能,总之...别发梦了
At least not on foot
至少徒步是不可能
That is one ugly ass bird.
那只丑陋的雀鸟
Dear Billy,
亲爱的比利
this place is hell.
这地方简直是地狱
And monsters exist.
怪兽确实存在
Under beds and signing paychecks
就在床下底
- Come on, man.   - Seems like...
- 拜托了  - 这似是
maybe he wants to go kill that ape instead of getting us off this island?
也许他是想去杀猩猩而不是离开这岛
Yeah!
对
Are we even gonna make it?
我们赶得到吗?
- Make what?   - The EXFIL!
- 赶得到什么?  - 到撤出点
We gotta be there in three days!
我们要在三天内到达!
We'll make it, we're gonna make it.
我们会赶到,来得及的
Yeah, but, Cole what happens if Chapman's not...
是柯尔,但要是查普曼出事...?
hey, the Colonel said he's there, he's there.
中校说他在那里,他就在那里
We were this close to getting it working.
我们差一点就令它启动
Me and Gunpei were gonna take off for the open sea, trying to get home.
我和军平打算开出外海,设法回家
That's when one of them things got him.
此时一只怪物杀了他
There she is.
船在那里
Well, that's lovely.
造型很可爱
You're damn right.
算你有眼光
Does this thing even float?
这东西浮得起来吗?
Me and Gunpei spent six years of our lives buliding this thing.
我和军平花了六年建造这艘船
She's called the Grey Fox.
船名是灰狐号
And she floats.
它浮得起来
Pulled the engine parts from my P-51 and his old Zero.
从我和他的战机取出引擎及零件
Found a B-29 on the beach one day. That was something.
还在海滩发现一架B-29轰炸机,那很有用
You gotta be kidding me.
你别开玩笑
That thing looks like it's made out of pure tetanus.
这东西可会害人得破伤风
I know she ain't pretty to look at,
这东西的确不起眼
but it's nothing a couple of extra hands can't fix.
而且修不好也是白废
Unless you got a better idea, I suggest we get cracking
除非你们另有高见,我建议我们手快点
All right.
好吧
Come on, get up!
加油,起来
Well, would you look at that?
看,那里
It bleeds.
它流血了
- Wha...   - We did that.
- 哗...  - 是我们下的手
We hook up with Chapman,
我们要跟查普曼会合
there's enough munitions on that downed Sea Stallion
那架坠落的海种马,载有足够的弹药
to finish the job.
能作出了结
Magnificent.
太壮观了
You know why I carry this instead of an M-16?
知道为何我带这个,而不带M16步枪?
Took it off a farmer fighting for the NVA.
由为越军而战的农夫手上抢来
He surrendered right after we leveled his village.
我们一铲平他的村落,他就投降了
He was 50 years old.
他50岁了
Said he'd never even seen a gun till we showed up.
说在我们出现前未见过枪
Sometimes, an enemy doesn't exist.
有时敌人并不存在
till you go looking for one.
直到你紧追着假想敌
What happens when they show up on your doorstep?
当敌人出现在你门口时,你会怎样?
I'll still have his gun.
我还是会拿着他的枪
Best of luck with that, soldier.
士兵,祝好运
Okay. So, we've got 48 hours to make it to the North Shore.
好,我们有48小时赶到北岸
Slivko, do you know what you're koing back there?
史利哥,知道你在修什么吧?
Yeah, pop's a mechanic.
当然,我爸是技师
If I can't fix this, he'll disown me.
修不好他会不认我
If he ever sees me again.
如果他还能再看到我
Hold the phone there, Churchill.
暂停一下,英国佬
Russia was our ally.
俄罗斯是我们的同盟国
Now, you're saying we're at war with them?
而你说我们正在跟他们作战?
It is more of a cold war.
比较像是冷战
Cold War like
冷战是指
that they take the summers off?
他们夺走夏天?
What about the Cubs? The cubs win a world series yet?
那小熊队呢?有赢得世界大赛吗?
The Cubs?
小熊队?
Man, not even close.
拜托,有排未轮到
Were they ever good?
他们有强过吗?
Happens to be my team. Where are you from?
我最支持的球队,你来自哪里?
- Detroit.   - Okay.
- 底特律  - 好
Whoa, yeah, the tigers. Did they win at all this year?
老虎队,他们今年赢了吗?
- I do not know.   - I doubt it. Yeah.
- 我不知道  - 我怀疑 真的
I'd pick the cubbies over the tigers and day.
我买小熊赢老虎...
Hey, Who do you think would win in a fight? A tiger or a Cub?
唏,老虎对小熊边个赢?
A tiger would win.
老虎会赢
Yeah, because the cubs is a baby bear.
因为小熊是幼熊
A full-grown tiger can eat a baby bear.
成年的老虎能吃掉幼熊
Just gotta think it through.
要多动脑筋
We also put a man on the moon.
人类也登上月球了
No kidding?
真定假?
What did they do? Just leave him up there?
他们干了什么?只把他丢在那里?
What's he eating?
他要吃什么?
Tang. Spam
罐装橙汁,罐头午餐肉
Come on, we're losing daylight.
快手点,天色快暗了
Fox Leader. this is Chapman, over.
狐队长,这是查普曼,完毕
Dear Billy...
亲爱的比利...
Sometimes, life just punch you in the balls
有时人生就是会给你致命一击
Damn it.
可恶
What kind of music is that?
这是什么音乐?
What happened to swing?
摇摆乐怎么了?
Benny Goodman?
班尼古德曼?
You're like a time-traveler man.
好像时空旅行者
I'm telling you, this is the new sound.
听好了,这才是新的声音
1944年
1973年
雷格利球场,芝加哥小熊的家
I don't know if I'm gonna like whoever's under this beard.
不知道我剃了须会像谁
I really hope that thing you call a boat
希望你称为船的那东西
can get us upriver in 36 hours.
36小时内可带我们到上游
Because if we miss that window
如果错过时机
we're, uh, literally, up a creek.
我们就要留下做土著了
When I first wrote that paper on the Hollow Earth theory,
我最初写地空说的论文时
the whole committee laughed out loud
全委员会都放声大笑
Not Randa.
除了朗达
The one guy in the crowd who actually took me seriously.
那群人当中唯一认真对我的人
It felt good.
那种感觉很好
Then I thought he was crazy when he said the earth was full of monsters.
然后他说地球满是怪兽,以为他疯了
I can't tell when I am talking or when I'm not talking.
我分不清我在说话或没在说话
You are talking.
你在说话
- Am I?   - Yes.
- 是吗?  - 是的
- I'm talking?   - Yes.
- 我在说话?  - 对
Your mouth is moving
你的嘴巴在动
What?
什么?
I'm gonna stab you by the end of the night.
我会在半夜插你一刀
Really?
真的?
Just kidding.
开玩笑
If the boat doesn't work, we'll just take the train.
如果船发动不了,就改搭火车
Isn't it odd,
诡异的是
the most dangerous places are always the most beautiful?
最危险的地方始终最美丽
I'm trying to take a long-exposure photograph
我想拍一张长曝光的照片
but my flashlight broke
但我的闪光灯坏了
Try this.
试试这个
Thank you.
谢谢
皇家空军
- Royal Air Force?   - It was my father's.
- 皇家空军  - 是我爸的
He threw it to me from the train as he rolled off to fight the Nazis.
他出发去打纳粹时从火车上掟给我
He was like John Wayne to me.
他就像是我的尊荣
Some kind of mythic hero.
某种神话的英雄
Did he come back?
他有回来吗?
His plane went down near Hamburg.
他的飞机坠落在汉堡附近
They searched for him for months but...
他们搜寻他几个月,但...
I suppose no man comes home from war.
我想没人会从战争中回家
Not really.
不是真的回来
Mills, quit dicking around. I'm going on perimeter.
米尔斯,别浪费时间,我要去检查周边
Colonel Packard,
帕卡德中校
this mission to the crash site is folly
前往坠机地点的任务并不明智
I understand going after your man.
我能理解你寻人心切
But the rest of it...
但除此之外...
This is beyond us
这不是我们能力所及
You don't like the way I'm running things?
你不喜欢我的处事方式?
You know where the door is.
想走人随你
You set this in motion when you put this place on the map.
你促成这场行动,硬闯这神秘异地
And I will not cut and run.
但我绝不会临阵逃跑
I know an enemy when I see it.
我看到敌人时就知道
This man's name was Gunpei Ikari.
这个人的名字是井狩军平
But you take away the uniforms
但只要脱去制服
and the war...
撇开战争
he became my brother.
他就成为我的兄弟
And we swore we'd never leave each other behind
我们发誓绝对不会丢下对方
Let's get off this island.
让我们离开这座岛吧
Owe, Not yet!
噢 还未可以!
- Prime the lines.   - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 把油加满  - 好、好、好
Wind it up, let's go!
搞掂,出发
Keep going!
继续转
Third time's the charm. Here we go, here we go
第三次就会成功,加油,加油
let's go, let's go, let's go.
加油,加油,加油
Come on, come on, come on.
拜托,拜托,拜托
Yes.
好了
Yes! Yes!
是的 发动了
I guess this is goodbye.
该是道别的时候了
Thank you.
谢谢
If you're ever in Chicago, look me up, I guess.
如果你们来芝加哥,记得找我
Here, no. Let me help.
拿来,让我帮忙
Man's gotta do what...ow!
男人就该...噢!
Are you okay?
你没事吧?
I'm Okay, I'm okay.
我没事
Allow me.
让我来吧
You should see me in the library.
妳该在图书馆认识我
I got a wife.
我有个妻子
Had a wife.
曾经有个妻子
Have a wife?
那妻子还在吗?
Guess I don't know anymore.
我已经不得而知了
We got hitched right before I deplyed.
我们在我参战前结婚
Got a telegram from her the day before I got shot down.
被击落的前一天收到她的电报
She said we just had our baby boy.
她说我们的儿子刚出生
I got a son out there.
我在世上有个儿子
Grown man I've never met
我从没见过的成年人
Yeah, she definitely thinks you're dead, man.
他一定认为你已经死了
Hey!
喂!
I'm just saying
我只是说说
You don't know that.
很难说
You'd be surprised how long people wait.
你会很惊讶人能等待多久
Ah, truth is, I don't expect them to be waiting.
事实上,我不指望他们等待
I'd be fine either way.
等或不等都没问题
I just want one last chance to see them.
我只想要一次机会与他们见面
That'd be good enough for me.
就心满意足了
We're gonna get you home.
我们会送你回家的
Fox Five, come back.
狐5号,回复
Is there anyone out there?
那里有人吗?
Hey! This is Fox Five. We hear you.
这是狐5号,我们听到你们了
Yeah! We're on a boat...
对,我们在船上...
- We're on a boat headed up north on river   - A boat?
- 从河上往北走  - 船?
Where'd you all get a boat?
你们哪里弄到船的?
We met this, like, crazy Santa Clause, a time-traveler guy from World War II
一个疯癫圣诞老人,二战时空旅行者
You'll meet him.
你会见到他的
What kind of boat y'all got?
你们弄来什么船?
It is more of, like, a plane than a boat, really.
其实更像是飞机多过一艘船,真的
Let's call it a "ploat".
就称它做"飞艇"
We're on a ploat
我们在飞艇上
We need their location Slivko.
史利哥,问他们的位置
Send up a flare so we can find you..
发信号弹,让我们找到你们
Roger that, Fox Five.
收到,狐5号
Fire in the hole!
发射信号弹
There!
在那里
Yes!
好了
I repeat, we have a visual. Two klicks to our north.
看到了,在我们北方2公里
Roger that, Fox Five. Fox One, out.
收到,狐5号,狐1号结束
Rendezvous point, one hour.
一小时后到会合点
Mount up!
上路了
Can we fit everybody?
船可载所有人吗?
Yes!
太好了!
We are going home!
我们要回家了
Get Down!
趴低!
What the hell, man?
那到底是什么?
He's gone.
他没救了
Everybody, grab your gear. We have to keep moving.
拿好各自的装备,我们要继续走
We'll go ashore, meet up with Packard
我们会上岸,跟帕卡德会合
No. No. Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
不,不,等等 等一下!
Is nobody gonna say anything about the...?
没人要说点什么,刚才...
He's gone!
他走了!
And he ain't coming back. There's nothing to say.
他不会回来了,没什么好说的
Oh, my god.
我的天啊!
That flare was only two klicks north
他们的信号弹在北面仅2公里
They should be here soon.
应该很快会到
Unless they were eaten by something that's bigger than us.
除非被比人类大的怪物生吞
Ah! Holy shit!
呀!老天!
Slivko!
史利哥
Thought you were taking a dirt nap by now, slivko.
我以为你死了
Never thought I'd see you guys again.
没想到能再见到你们
- I thought you were crazy.   - I wish I had been.
- 你还剩多少人?  - 你看到的人
- What's the count?   - What you see
- 你们有多少人?  - 就你看到的
is what I got.
就是全部了
We lost one too.
我们也失去一个人
Good to see you, fellas!
很高兴认识你们
Who the hell is this?
这是何方神圣?
We picked up a hitchhiker.
我们让他搭便车
Lieutenant Hank Marlow of the 45th pursuit squadron of the 15th.
第15驱逐机中队45步兵团的汉克?马隆中尉
You've been here since World War II?
你自二战以来就在这里?
Yes sir. I miss the parade?
是长官,我错过阅兵了?
I'll be damned.
真想不到
Snap to. Lieutenant.
敬礼,中尉
We're gonna get him home, sir.
我们会送他回家
If we follow this river,
只要沿着这条河
We'll make it to the boat and we'll make it to the north shore in time.
就会赶上船,及时到达北岸
That sounds good.
好主意
But we're not leaving yet.
但我们还不能离开
Still got a man out there, Conrad.
康拉德,还有一人失踪
Wait a second. You got someone out there?
等一下,还有一人失踪?
Chapman.
查普曼
He's with the downed Sea Stallion just west of here.
他在坠落的海种马旁,在西边
West? We can't go west!
西边?我们不能往西
That's where the skull things live.
骷髅怪兽就住在那里
We have an old saying here. "East is best, west is worst!".
土语有话"东面好地方,西面生毒疮"
That's why we say it!
这样说是有道理的
You know, southwest...
至于西南...
We could talk about that
还可以商量
But we're gonna need a lot more guns if you're gonna go west.
但往西的话需要更多枪炮
Guys. I think that we should listen to Marlow.
各位,我们应该听马隆的
This is crazy.
这太疯狂了
Hey.
老弟
Your job is finding lost men, right?
你的工作是找到失踪的人,对吧?
Okay, sir.
你话事
But if we reach that position, and he's not there,
但如果我们到达那里而他不在
we don't send out a search party.
不会派出搜索队
We're back here by nightfall, understood?
傍晚前回来这里,清楚吗?
In 24 hours, we have to be on the other side of this island.
我们要在24小时内赶到岛的另一边
Roger that. Hear you loud and clear.
了解,听得一清二楚
All right, you heard the man. Moving out in 10.
你们听到他了,十分钟后出发
This is a good group of boys.
真是一班好兄弟
We're all gonna die together out here.
我们会拥着一起送死
You're a good group of boys to die with. I'll tell you that much.
我可以话庆幸能跟你们拥着死
You shouldn't have come here.
你们不该来这里的
Don't forget to tell me this is a bad idea?
别忘记提醒我这是个烂主意
This is a bad idea.
这是个烂主意
Yeah, you smell that?
有闻到吗?
That's death.
那是死亡的味道
What the hell is this place?
这到底是什么地方?
This is what's left of Kong's parents.
这是金刚父母的遗骸
I've taken enough photos of mass graves to recognize one
我拍了够多乱葬岗,总算认得出来
The crash site's just on other side of this valley
坠机地点在这山谷另一边
We'll cross through and make it to the highest point west.
我们会穿过山谷爬上西方的最高点
Ah ah...
呀 那...
This place is a real no-no, sir.
这地方是禁忌
We need to be going to the north side right now.
我们需要立刻去北边
And you're welcome to do that, my man.
你请便,老兄
By your self.
你请便
I'm not leaving Jack out there. Now, Who's with me?
我不会丢下积克,谁会跟我去?
We can make it.
我们会成功的
You're mightly right, we can make it.
对极了,我们会成功的
Now stay sharp. Keep an eye out.
好,保持灵敏,随时警惕
I've only got here 28 years. What do I know?
我在这里只待了28年,那会知
Cole,
柯尔
We don't got time for that, man. Put the cigarette out.
没时间了 把烟弄熄
Watch those fumes!
小心沼气
Idiots.
笨蛋
Let's go. We gotta move!
走吧,我们要赶快
Run!
快逃
In Here!
躲在这里!
Quiet.
安静
I told you this damn place was a no-no.
我就说这鬼地方是禁忌
Damn it. Shh!
该死
积克?查普曼
All right, let's move.
好,快走
Rally on me.
队伍跟着我
Rally up! Rally up!
好了 动作要快
Somebody cover the civilians' six! Let's Move!
谁去掩护后方平民,赶快
Oh shit.
死火
Randa!
朗达!
Set up the 50!
预备机关枪
宁死不屈
Run
快跑
Bring the torch! Do your thing!
拿喷火器来,烧死牠
Slivko!
史利哥
Gas!
有毒气
毒气
Marlow! The sword!
马隆,剑给我
Slivko, hang on!
史利哥,等我
This thing's moving!
怪兽正冲过来!
Now, look, Colonel.
听着,中校
You may outrank me,
你可能官阶比我高
but I've been here a hell a lot longer.
但我待在这里可久了
And I'm telling you
我郑重告诉你
that thing that just shredded us was only the first of them
刚才只是其中一只已令我们损伤惨重
Now we're on their turf,
我们踩入了牠们地盘
and we need to turn back toot sweet!
需要立即回头
Not as long as Chapman's still out there.
只要查普曼还在,就不会回头
I'm Sorry, Colonel Packard.
很遗憾,帕卡德中校
Chapman is dead.
查普曼已经死了
Doesn't change a thing!
计划不变
We're still going to that crash site.
我们仍会去坠机地点
What's at that crash site that you want so badly?
你到底想在坠机地点找到什么?
Weapons!
武器
Enough to kill it.
足以杀掉牠
Kong didn't kill Chapman.
金刚没杀查普曼
But It did kill these men!
但牠杀了这些人
My men!
我的兄弟
You can't kill Kong, Colonel.
中校,你不能杀金刚
Kong is God on this island.
金刚是这座岛上的神
He's the only thing keeping them lizard things in the ground.
只有牠能阻挡大蜥蜴爬出地面
He's right, Colonel. We can't kill Kong.
他说得对,中校,金刚不能杀
Now, that other creature?
至于另一种怪物?
That's the threat. And there are more of them down there.
才是威胁,那处下面有更多
If you take away that species' natural competition
如果你破坏物种的自然竞争
they'll proliferate out of control.
Then we'll end them, too!
那我们也要终结牠们
After we bring this thing down.
在我们拿下金刚之后
I can't let you do that. Colonel.
中校,我不能让你那样做
Wait! Hold your fire.
等等,停手
This is one war we are not gonna lose.
我们绝不会输掉这场战争
Nuts!
他疯了
You hear me? This is nuts!
你听到我了,这简直疯了
Please! You need to listen to us!
拜托,你需要听我们的
We're not at war, Colonel. You're making a mistake.
我们不是在交战,你会铸成大错
Your lies got my men killed!
你们的谎言害我死下属
- And you're gonna get us all killed.   - Not our fight.
- 但你会害死所有人  - 别加把咀
Whose side are you on, Captain?
上尉,你站哪一边?
Okay, Colonel.
好吧,中校
You'll find your Sea Stallion three klicks up that ridge
你深入那山脊三公里找你的海种马
Now, I'm gonna take these civillians back to the boat.
我会带这些平民回到船上
And we'll wait for you there.
我们在那里等你们
All right?
好吗?
Saddle up!
准备出发
Let's go kill this thing!
去杀掉金刚吧
Steve,
史提夫
You running with the big dogs or staying on the porch?
你跟我们打怪兽或跟他们去冲凉?
I don't wanna be on the porch.
我不想去冲凉
Marlow, You okay?
马隆,你没事吧?
We need to stop him.
我们需要阻止他
You wanna talk with him about it agian? He seemed to really go for it the first time.
你又想跟他争辩?他一开始就很坚决
He's losing his grip.
他失了控
Now, follow me,
跟着我
and we'll get off this rock alive.
我们会活着离开这座岛
Dear Billy...
亲爱的比利
I'm just trying to get home to you and your Mom.
我正设法回家找你和你妈
You be strong, now.
你要坚强喔
Much love.
超爱你的
Make sure those get back to his family.
确定把这些东西送回他的家人
Dear Billy...
亲爱的比利
Your dad was one of the best to ever do it.
你爸是最优秀的军人
There's water close by.
这附近有水源
Are you lost? Which way?
你迷路了吗?走哪一边?
Hang on.
等等
Wait here.
在这里等
I've got to get to high ground to find the river.
我要到高处找河流
Hey! I'm coming, too.
唏,我也去
I'll be right here.
我在这里守着
Keep your eyes open.
保持警戒
Up in the trees, too.
也要小心树上
Why?
为什么?
Ants.
有蚂蚁
Big ones.
大蚂蚁
There's one.
那里就有一只
Sounds like a bird, but it's a fucking ant.
听起来像鸟,但却是蚂蚁
Gather up everything you can, including those seismic charges.
尽量收集弹药,包括炸药包
They got his attention the first time.
第一次投弹就引起了牠的注意
This is a bad idea.
这是个烂主意
Let's just get on with it
见机行事吧
Mills, Cole,
米尔斯、柯尔
let's prep this ordnance.
准备好炸弹
Make him a special gift out of that Naplam.
给牠汽油弹特别大礼
The boat must be around that bend.
船一定在河弯附近
We have to go, Now.
我们该走了,立刻
Don't shoot!
别开枪
Conrad, which way are we going?
康拉德,我们要走哪边?
You three need to go back to the boat. It's that way.
你们三人要回去船上,是那边
Wait for us till dawn.
等我们到黎明
If we're not back by then,
到时候不见我们回来
just go.
就先走吧
You ain't gotta twist my arm.
没你吩咐我也会走
Where are you two going?
你们俩要去哪里?
We're going to save Kong.
我们要去救金刚
Not without me, pal.
老友,少不了我
Oh, dear.
老天!
Men!
兄弟们
Place your chargers.
预备进攻
It's time to show Kong
该是时候向金刚证明
that man is king!
人类才是王者
Arm one.
一号炸弹
Arm Two.
二号炸弹
Arm three.
三号炸弹
Packard!
帕卡德
Don't do it.
千万不要
I asked you fellas nice the first time.
我第一次跟你们好好说
We don't wanna fight here, Packard.
别在这里开战,帕卡德
This thing brought us down! It killed my men!
这怪兽害我们坠机,杀了我的下属
Kong was just defending his territory.
金刚只是在捍卫自己的地盘
We are soldiers!
我们是军人
We do the dirty work!
我们负责干肮脏勾当
So our families and our countrymen don't have to be afraid!
好让家人和同胞不必害怕
They shouldn't even know a thing like this exists!
他们甚至不该知道这种怪物存在
You've lost your mind.
你疯了
Put that detonator down.
放下引爆器
Stop!
住手
The world is bigger than this.
别把世界想得这么局限
Bitch, please!
女人,别多事!
Slivko, get her out of there!
史利哥,把她带走
You know it's the wrong thing to do, son.
你明知这样做是错的,孩子
Put it down, sir.
放下引爆器,长官
Packard!
帕卡德
Come on.
认清形势
It's over.
结束了
That's the big one.
那就是大只的
Fall back.
撤退
Go!
快走
Colonel.
中校
Sir!
长官
Die you motherfucker...
你去死吧,你这畜牲
- Kong.   - Kong's down. Let's go!
- 金刚  - 金刚倒下了,快走
They told us to leave at dawn
他们叫我们黎明时离开
- I know.   - It's dawn.
- 我知道  - 已经黎明了
I know!
我知道啦!
So what are we going to do?
那我们该怎么办?
This is the edge of the island.
这是岛的边缘
Weaver, get up on those rocks and fire a flare.
玮桦,爬上岩石发信号弹
With any luck, Brooks will see it.
够运布鲁克就会看见
We'll buy you time.
我们会帮妳争取时间
This way.
这边
Come on. Every second counts.
快点,分秒不能浪费
Cole!
柯尔
Come on, man, we gotta fall back.
过来,我们要撤退
Go live your life.
享受你们的人生
Get out of here.
离开这里
- Cole, no!   - Cole!
- 柯尔 不!  - 柯尔!
Cole, no! Stop!
柯尔 不
- Cole!   - Cole!
- 柯尔...  - 柯尔
No! Don't!
不要啊
Cole!
柯尔
Come on. Come on. You son of a bitch.
来啊 来啊...你这头畜牲
Come on! Go!
快跑,快啊
快点 走!
Come on! Hurry!
快上来,快
Come on!
快啊
Marlow, a little help here?
马隆,这里需要帮手
I got it, She's temperamental. Watch out!
让我来,这支枪发脾气,小心!
- Clear   - Okay!
- 清除  - 好
Come on, you bastard!
来啊,你这畜牲
Weaver!
玮桦
Weaver? Weaver. Weaver.
玮桦,玮桦,玮桦
Hey, hey hey hey!
嘿,嘿 嘿 嘿!
You're okay?
妳没事了
So what do you think, fellas?
兄弟们,你们觉得呢?
This way to Key West?
去佛州西屿?
I think it is, brother.
应该是,兄弟
This place will change.
这个地方会改观
Word will get out.
消息会传开来
It always does.
迟早的事
Well, it's not coming from us.
但不会是由我们传开
We will meet again.
?我们会重逢
Don't know where. Don't know when
?不知在哪里,不知在何时
But I know we'll meet again.
?但我知道我们会重逢
Here we go now to the cub half of number 8
各位,进入第8局小熊队进攻
If you want to see a crowd go crazy,
如果你想看到一群人疯狂
see what happens if this guy hits one right now.
那就等着看这位选手的击球吧
Fly ball, very deep.
球飞得很远 是好球
An the impossible dream just became the possible dream!
不可能的梦也能成为真实了!
You just gonna sit there?
你们打算坐在那里?
In the dark?
坐在黑暗处?
You're enjoying this, right?
你们乐在其中,对吧?
Is this funny for you?
你们把这当乐趣?
I promise I won't tell the Russians
我保证我不会告诉俄国人
I promised I will tell the Russians
我保证我会告诉俄国人
She's gonna tell the Russians
她要去告诉俄国人
Why are you keeping us here?
为什么把我们关在这里?
I wanna go home
我想要回家
We get it. There was no Island, we were never on an Island
我们懂了,根本没有岛 我们从没上过这岛屿
Island?
岛?
What Island?
什么岛?
Brooks, what the hell is going on?
布鲁克,这到底是怎么回事?
Welcome to Monarch
欢迎莅临君主计划
This Island is just the beginning
这座岛只是开端
There's more out there
还有更多
What do you mean, "more"?
"更多"是什么意思?
This world never belonged to us
这世界从来不属于我们
It belonged to them
而是属于牠们的
The question is how long before they take it back
问题是牠们几时会抢回去
Kong is not the only king
金刚不是唯一的王
君主 最高机密
第8区 更多威胁